Hello friends, welcome to TP Inn Sites.
In today's video, we will talk about
how to use the Star Health Insurance policy or its card and where it can be used.
Many people do
not know how to use it after buying the policy,
what is
its process for using it, so
I am going to tell you all about it in this video,
so please watch the video till the end. If
you are new to the channel, then
subscribe to the channel and like the video.
So let's start the video
[Music].
Before buying a Star Health Insurance policy, you need to know a few things in
advance. First of all, it is
important to know how many hospitals near you are
in the network list of Star Health Insurance Company, that is, they are
in its panel, with which hospitals are they associated,
which
hospitals are near you which are associated with Star Health.
You should
know this before buying the policy. If you do not know this, then
you will face problems later while making a claim
or while getting your treatment done.
Before that, whenever you
purchase a plan, you should know all its details.
You have to read the terms of the policy
carefully. If you are buying everything from your agent or
online portal, then
ask them everything and understand it before buying the plan so that
you do not face any problem while making a claim.
Many people purchase their policy and
also choose the plan, but
they do not know how to use it after making the health card
or after getting the policy. Is there a
waiting
period for it? Are there many other
things in it which they do not
know. So I have made this video for those people. So please
share this video with such people so that they
know how to use the Star Health Insurance
card. When we
buy a health insurance policy from Star
Health, then its waiting period is
within the individual policy. Individual
means, within the policy taken by ourselves, there is a
waiting period of one month.
Only after one month, we can
use our health insurance card or policy for our treatment.
We cannot use it before that. There is a
waiting period of one month.
Individual policy is there in all the policies, it is there
in Star Health also,
so it is important for us to know about it in advance,
so after completion of one month, we can
use it for our treatment in any network hospital,
it will be valid
only in admitted cases, we will
consult a doctor in OPD and bring medicines,
in that case it will not be valid, it will be valid only
in admitted cases, if you need to be admitted
and even in admission you will need to be hospitalized for minimum 24 hours, only then
you will be able to use it, there are
two types of health insurance policies, one is
individual policy and the other is corporate
policy, I have
made separate videos on both of these, still I will
tell you a little about it,
individual policy is done by you, you have
chosen your own plan after understanding it or
you have purchased the policy from any agent or portal of your choice
and corporate policy is either
you are working in a private bank or any
private company, you are an
employee there and that company insures
you and your family, so it  When it
comes to corporate policies,
you have to observe a one-month waiting
period for individual policies before you
can use them. However, there's
no such thing in corporate policies. You can use them
as soon as you need them
after your health card is issued. However, wherever you're
working, whether you've just joined a new job,
try to get your
health card issued as soon as you arrive. It takes
some time to process it within the corporate sector, and the
documentation process is a bit
slow. Therefore, whenever you take on a new
job, or join a company
or bank in a new location, you should keep this in
mind.
Before and after purchasing a Star Health insurance policy,
we should know
where our health card is valid,
which hospitals, and which
hospitals are within Star Health's network list.
Whenever we face a
medical emergency and
need treatment, we'll go
to a network hospital
and show our health
card. If the doctor determines
you need admission, we'll be sure to go to a network hospital and show our health card.  In that case,
your health card will be used for cashless treatment.
Cashless treatment and
resource claim will be available only if that
hospital
is not in the network list of Star Health Insurance.
We should already know these things. If we
go to a network hospital,
we will get cashless treatment there. If we
go to a non-network hospital without seeing or inquiring, then for
whatever treatment we get, we will have to pay for it
from our own pocket. Later, that
bill will be sent to the insurance company through a rescission form. It may take from
one to two months to be cleared. So,
we need to know these things in
advance.
You can go to the website of Star Health Insurance and see the list of your network hospitals. If
you still do not understand or are
unable to find out, then there will be
a toll
free number of the health insurance company on your policy or on your health card. You
can also find out from them by talking to customer care there. They will tell you the area-wise
list of hospitals on the panel, which are available in
this pin
code or this location.  If it is
available in our list above then you can find out from two things also, the
third thing is that from
whom you are buying the policy, either
from an agent or there is an online
portal, then from there also you can find out
which hospital in our vicinity or nearby is
in the network list of Star Health Insurance Company, so in today's
video I told you people that
how can you use your health card or health policy of Star Health Insurance Company from the beginning till the end,
I have explained its complete process
to you people through this video, if
you liked the video then like it and
subscribe to the channel, if
you have any question in your mind then
write in the comment section, I will answer it,
see you in the next video, till then
hello